McCroskey Hall Records 1920-1968, 2013-2014
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
McCroskey Hall Records
1920-1968, 2013-2014
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC) Holland and Terrell Libraries Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 138
approximate 150 items 2 linear feet 4 containers
The records consist of meeting minutes, hall handbooks, guest book, dance programs, logs of activities and a social events record. The logs contain summaries of events and activities along with newspaper clippings, pictures, dance programs and favors. The social events record has details of each event, such as the menu and names of committee members, kept for the Student Activities Committee.
Organizational History:
McCroskey Hall was built in 1920 and named after long-time Regent R. C. McCroskey. It has consistently been used as a women's dormitory except during World War II and the early 1950's when it was used for male housing. The house government consists of elected officers who form an executive council. Kroskey Club was formed in 1931 as an organization of selected upperclassmen to support the council and plan special activities. It was disbanded in 1937.
The records of McCroskey Hall, 1920-1968, are arranged in a single series. They have been grouped functionally and then chronologically. The records consist of meeting minutes, hall handbooks, guest book, dance programs, scrapbooks, logs of activities and a social events record. The logs contain summaries of events and activities along with newspaper clippings, pictures, dance programs and favors. The social events record has details of each event, such as the menu and names of committee members, kept for the Student Activities Committee.
The Collection is open for research use.
The records of McCroskey Hall were transferred to Washington State University Libraries prior to 1970 (WSU 109). On May 8, 2015 a single 2013-2014 scrapbook was received and placed into the collection and the end of box 1.
Washington State University. McCroskey Hall--Archives; State College of Washington. McCroskey Hall.; Washington State University. McCroskey Hall--Records and correspondence; Washington State University--Buildings--Archives
Dormitories--Washington (State)--Pullman--Archives
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- Hall House Meeting Minutes
  - 1920-1932, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1932-1938, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1938-1943, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1956, 8 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1964-1968, 58 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Kroskey Club Records, 1931-1937; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Guest Book, 1921-1945; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Hall Handbooks, 1948-1955; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Social Chairmen Book, 1935-1936; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Social Events Record, 1947-1951; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Dance Programs, 1937-1942; 8 items (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Scrapbook, 2013-2014; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 11.1)
- Log of McCroskey Hall
  - 1920-1935, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1936-1944, 61 items (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1945-1946, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1946-1948, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1948-1951, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 16)